NIGHTCLUBBING Archive by Pat Ivers and Emily Armstrong 1970-2009 (Bulk 1975-1980) MSS 305
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series I: Performances
  - Womanland with Millionairs Overnight at ETC Studios, undated (Box 8, Media ID: 305.0148)
- Series II: Interviews
  Series II contains video interviews with various musicians, performance artists, critics, and writers involved in the New York City punk scene. Many of the videos are undated. The dated interviews were all made in the 2000s except for one recording from 1977.
  - Joey Arias at Theater, March 10, undated (Box 11, Media ID: 305.0181)
    Original format: Betacam SX
    Alternate Title: Joey Arias at Theater, March 23
  - James Chance - Tape 1, undated (Box 11, Media ID: 305.0179)
    Alternate Title: James Chance at CBGB - Tape 1 of 2
  - James Chance - Tape 2, undated (Box 11, Media ID: 305.0180)
    Alternate Title: James Chance at CBGB - Tape 2 of 2
  - Cheeta Chrome at LA, June 9 [Year Unknown] (Box 11, Media ID: 305.0197)
    Original format: Mini DV
  - Jay Dee Daugherty at CBGB, June 9 [Year Unknown] (Box 11, Media ID: 305.0209)
    Duration: 42 minutes
  - Richard Hell - Tape 1, March 24, 2007 (Box 11, Media ID: 305.0170)
    Alternate Title: Richard Hell at Winship's; March 24, 2007 - Tape 1 of 2
  - Richard Hell - Tape 2, March 25, 2007 (Box 11, Media ID: 305.0171)
    Alternate Title: Richard Hell at Winship's; March 25, 2007 - Tape 2 of 2
  - Hilly & Cosmo at CBGB, May 9, 1977 (Box 11, Media ID: 305.0212)
    Black & White, Color, Sound
  - Hilly Interview, undated (Box 11, Media ID: 305.0176)
    Alternate Title: [Hilly Krystal at CBGBs, March 2]
  - John Holstrom at Orchard Street (Year Unknown), May 1 (Box 11, Media ID: 305.0193)
  - John Holstrom 2 at Orchard Street (Year Unknown), May 11 (Box 11, Media ID: 305.0194)
  - Ivan Julian at Ivan's Studio, (Year Unknown), June 9 (Box 11, Media ID: 305.0198)
  - Ivan Julian & Marcia Resnick at Ivan's Studio and Marcia's Apartment, (Year Unknown), June 9 (Box 11, Media ID: 305.0199)
  - Lenny Kaye at Brooklyn Home, February 20, 2004 (Box 11, Media ID: 305.0182)
    Alternate Title: Lenny Kaye at Brooklyn Home, February 20, 2004 1/2
  - Lenny Kaye at Brooklyn Home, February 20, 2004 (Box 11, Media ID: 305.0183)
  - Stephanie Kaye - Tape 1, undated (Box 11, Media ID: 305.0177)
    Alternate Title: Stephanie Kaye at Bowery Loft; February 9 - Tape 1 of 2
  - Stephanie Kaye - Tape 2, undated (Box 11, Media ID: 305.0178)
    Alternate Title: Stephanie Kaye at Bowery Loft; February 9 - Tape 2 of 2
  - Arto Lindsay at Orchard Street, March 23 2002 (Box 11, Media ID: 305.0188)
    Alternate Title: Arto Lindsay at Orchard Street, March 23 2002 1/2
  - Arto Lindsay at Orchard Street, March 23 2002 (Box 11, Media ID: 305.0189)
    Item is currently unavailable.
    Alternate Title: Arto Lindsay at Orchard Street, March 23 2002 2/2
  - Richard Lloyd - Tape 1, May 11, 2002 (Box 11, Media ID: 305.0174)
    Alternate Title: Richard Lloyd at His Studio; May 10, 2002 - Tape 1 of 2
  - Richard Lloyd - Tape 2, April 10, 2002 (Box 11, Media ID: 305.0175)
    Alternate Title: Richard Lloyd at His Studio, April 10, 2002 - Tape 2 of 2
  - Lydia Lunch 1 at Orchard Street (Year Unknown), June 9 (Box 11, Media ID: 305.0207)
  - Lydia Lunch 2 at Orchard Street (Year Unknown), June 9 (Box 11, Media ID: 305.0208)
  - Walter Lure at Bayside Home (Year Unknown), May 2 (Box 11, Media ID: 305.0184)
    Alternate Title: Walter Lure at Bayside Home, May 2 [Year Unknown] 1/2
  - Walter Lure at Bayside Home (Year Unknown), May 11 (Box 11, Media ID: 305.0185)
    Alternate Title: Walter Lure at Bayside Home, May 11 [Year Unknown] 2/2
  - Pat Place at Pat's Loft (Year Unknown), June 9 (Box 11, Media ID: 305.0201)
  - Mark Ramone 1 at Orchard Street (Year Unknown), June 9 (Box 11, Media ID: 305.0205)
  - Mark Ramone 2 at Orchard Street (Year Unknown), June 9 (Box 11, Media ID: 305.0206)
  - Marcia Resnick 2 at Marcia's Apartment (Year Unknown), June 9 (Box 11, Media ID: 305.0200)
  - Michael Shore - Tape 1, undated (Box 11, Media ID: 305.0172)
    Duration: 30 minute
    Alternate Title: Michael Shore at MTV - Tape 1 of 2
  - Michael Shore - Tape 2, undated (Box 11, Media ID: 305.0173)
    Alternate Title: Michael Shore at MTV - Tape 2 of 2
  - Cynthia Sley at Pat's Loft (Year Unknown), June 9 (Box 11, Media ID: 305.0202)
    Original format: Format: Mini DV
  - David Thomas 1 at LA (Year Unknown), June 9 (Box 11, Media ID: 305.0196)
  - David Thomas 2 and Cheeta Chrome 1 at LA (Year Unknown), June 9 (Box 11, Media ID: 305.0195)
  - Tish and Snooky, undated (Box 11, Media ID: 305.0190)
  - Tish & Snooky 1 at Manic Panic (Year Unknown), May 11 (Box 11, Media ID: 305.0191)
  - Tish & Snooky 2 and Scratchy at Manic Panic and Orchard Street (Year Unknown), May 11 (Box 11, Media ID: 305.0192)
  - Roy Trakin 1 at LA (Year Unknown), June 9 (Box 11, Media ID: 305.0203)
  - Roy Trakin 2 at LA (Year Unknown), June 9 (Box 11, Media ID: 305.0204)
  - Alan Vega at Orchard Street, March 2, 2002 (Box 11, Media ID: 305.0186)
    Alternate Title: Alan Vega at Orchard Street, March 11 [Year Unknown] 1/2
  - Alan Vega at Orchard Street (Year Unknown), March 11 (Box 11, Media ID: 305.0187)
    Alternate Title: Alan Vega at Orchard Street, March 11 [Year Unknown] 2/2
  - Jeff Magnum, undated (Box 11, Media ID: 305.0210)
  - Arto/Suicide, undated (Box 11, Media ID: 305.0211)
- Series III: The Come-On's
  The seven videos in Series III comprise two shoots and rough edits of The Come-On’s video installation project. The project allowed participants to select to view a tape of a performer, or “seducer,” in a photo booth. Each tape featured a musician or artist from the downtown scene who attempted to “seduce” the viewer.
  - The Come-On's: Shoot 1, #1, undated (Box 12, Media ID: 305.0213)
  - The Come-On's: Shoot 1, #2, undated (Box 12, Media ID: 305.0214)
  - The Come-On's: Shoot 1, #3, undated (Box 12, Media ID: 305.0215)
  - The Come-On's: Shoot 2, #1, undated (Box 12, Media ID: 305.0216)
  - The Come-On's: Shoot 2, #2, undated (Box 12, Media ID: 305.0217)
  - The Come-On's: Rough Edit, undated (Box 12, Media ID: 305.0218)
  - The Come-On's: Rough Edit, undated (Box 12, Media ID: 305.0219)
- Series IV: Narrative Tapes
  The six videos in Series IV comprise narrative tapes, which functioned as the precursor to modern music videos. In each narrative tape, an artist’s performance is accompanied by thematically relevant stories, images, and video clips.
  - European Ashes, 1982 (Box 12, Media ID: 305.0223)
    Duration: 6 minutes
  - European Ashes, undated (Box 12, Media ID: 305.0224)
  - Boy's Backs, undated (Box 12, Media ID: 305.0221)
    Duration: 4 minutes
  - Chain of Fools, Boy's Backs, undated (Box 12, Media ID: 305.0220)
    Duration: 51 minutes
  - Samurai Toys, undated (Box 12, Media ID: 305.0225)
  - Surfclubbing, Rockabilly Romance, undated (Box 12, Media ID: 305.0222)
- Series V: Video Lounge
  The nineteen videos in Series V contain Video Lounge footage captured by Ivers and Armstrong. The artists created the Video Lounge format after being commissioned to design a video installation for the opening of the Danceteria nightclub in 1980. Video Lounge became a permanent feature at Danceteria but Ivers and Armstrong also included the format in the NIGHTCLUBBING television series, which showed video art, various video clips and footage, and musical performances.
  - Betty Boop Cartoons, undated (Box 12, Media ID: 305.0226)
  - Rich Reel, undated (Box 12, Media ID: 305.0227)
    Duration: 45 minutes
  - 1. Decade of Decadence 2. Elvis Costello Animation 3. David Johansen, undated (Box 12, Media ID: 305.0228)
    Duration: 44 minutes
  - Surf, undated (Box 13, Media ID: 305.0229)
  - Nutty Stuff, undated (Box 13, Media ID: 305.0230)
    Duration: 00:38:55
  - Japanese Sci-fi and Music Videos, undated (Box 13, Media ID: 305.0231)
    Duration: 58 minutes
  - Movie Stuff, undated (Box 13, Media ID: 305.0232)
  - Funny Stuff, undated (Box 13, Media ID: 305.0233)
  - Rockamerica, October 1980 (Box 13, Media ID: 305.0234)
  - Home Entertainment #4, undated (Box 13, Media ID: 305.0235)
    Duration: 1 hour 2 minutes
  - 1. Elvis Presley and Milton Bearl 2. Jane Mansfield, Mickey Rooney and Ronald Reagan 3."Rock Around the Clock" Trailer, undated (Box 13, Media ID: 305.0236)
  - Home Entertainment #2, undated (Box 13, Media ID: 305.0237)
  - Factory Records Music Videos, undated (Box 13, Media ID: 305.0238)
    Duration: 38 minutes
  - 1. Altered States 2. Superman Opening 3. Krypton Blows Up, etc., undated (Box 13, Media ID: 305.0239)
  - 1. "Debs Behind Bars" 2. Time Lapse Photography 3. Devo, etc., undated (Box 13, Media ID: 305.0240)
  - 1. "Ave Maria" 2.Change of Habit Trailer 3. Japanese Riot Squad Infomercial, etc., undated (Box 13, Media ID: 305.0241)
  - 1. Show Lumania 2. Shox Lumania 3. Island of Dr. Moreau, etc., undated (Box 13, Media ID: 305.0242)
  - 1. Eel + Octopus 2. Hindenberg 3. Keith Haring, etc., undated (Box 13, Media ID: 305.0243)
  - 1. Stones (old) 2. Public Image 3. Devo, etc., undated (Box 13, Media ID: 305.0244)
- Series VI: Nightclubbing
  The sixteen videos in Series VI contain episodes of the NIGHTCLUBBING television series that was broadcast as a local television show in New York City and was also screened at late night viewings at the Anthology Film Archives. While the majority of these recordings are undated, the dated videos were made during 1975-1980.
  - Dead Boys, 1977 (Box 10, Media ID: 305.0167)
  - Dead Boys, 1977 - 1979 (Box 9, Media ID: 305.0160)
  - Cramps, DNA, undated (Box 10, Media ID: 305.0169)
    Black & White/Color, Sound
  - Hardcore 2, undated (Box 10, Media ID: 305.0165)
  - Rock/Racism - CP, October 3, 1979 (Box 9, Media ID: 305.0156)
  - Kid Creaole & the Coconuts, undated (Box 9, Media ID: 305.0159)
  - "Live Girls": Stilettos, Erasers, Desire, undated (Box 10, Media ID: 305.0162)
  - Nuggets; Heartbreakers, undated (Box 9, Media ID: 305.0158)
  - Raybeats Swimming Pool Ques, undated (Box 9, Media ID: 305.0154)
  - "Real Rockers": Casualties; Heartbreakers, undated (Box 9, Media ID: 305.0161)
    Duration: 46 minutes
  - Revelons, Only Ones at CBGB, undated (Box 10, Media ID: 305.0168)
  - Roots of Hardcore; Hardcore Sampler: Dead Kennedys, Dead Boys, Heartbreakers, undated (Box 10, Media ID: 305.0166)
  - Student Teachers; Pinups, undated (Box 9, Media ID: 305.0157)
  - West Coast Offs, Dils, Dead Kennedys, undated (Box 10, Media ID: 305.0164)
  - West Coast; More Live Girls, undated (Box 9, Media ID: 305.0155)
  - History of the Heartbreakers, 1975 - 1980 (Box 10, Media ID: 305.0163)
- Series VII: Preservation Elements
  - Subseries A: Preservation Masters
    - Box 14: ID# 305.0001-305.0027 (Box 14)
    - Box 15: ID# 305.0028-305.0050 (Box 15)
    - Box 16: ID# 305.0051-305.0069 (Box 16)
    - Box 17: ID# 305.0070-305.0086 (Box 17)
    - Box 18: ID# 305.0087-305.0102 (Box 18)
    - Box 19: ID# 305.0103-305.0119 (Box 19)
    - Box 20: ID# 305.0120-305.0140 (Box 20)
    - Box 21: ID# 305.0141-305.0155 (Box 21)
    - Box 22: ID# 305.0156-305.0177 (Box 22)
    - Box 23: ID# 305.0178-305.0190 (Box 23)
    - Box 24: ID# 305.0191-305.0206 (Box 24)
    - Box 25: ID# 305.0207-305.0221 (Box 25)
    - Box 26: ID# 305.0222-305.0235 (Box 26)
    - Box 27: ID# 305.0236-305.0244 (Box 27)
  - Subseries B: Sub-masters
    - Box 28: ID# 305.0001-305.0096 (Box 28)
    - Box 29: ID# 305.0097-305.0184 (Box 29)
    - Box 30: ID# 305.0185-305.0244 (Box 30)
- Series VIII: Logs
  - Logs, 1975-80, undated (Binder A)
    Contains tape logs, copies, and playbills of performances dating between 1975 and 1980.
  - Logs, 1975-80, undated (Binder B)
- Series IX: Press Clippings
  - Press Clippings, 1979-1982 (Binder C)
    Newspaper articles, advertisements, and press releases from 1979-1982.
  - Press Clippings, 2000-2012 (Binder D)
    Newspaper and magazine clippings, advertisements, and press releases, both US and international, dating from 2000-2012.